Usama Qureshi

Game Developer, Graphic Designer, AR/VR Designer & Developer

Karachi, Pakistan usamaqh@gmail.com +(92) 346-5348843

To serve in a progressive organization offering job satisfaction, a challenging yet enjoyable work environment and vast opportunity for career development that utilizes & extends my multi-skill knowledge, capability & work experience.

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Work Experience

AR/VR Designer & Developer

Digichowk Pvt. Ltd. - Karachi February 2019 to Present

- To design & develop market required, industrial based interactive AR, VR, multi-purpose, multi-player & multi-platform applications.
- Team lead.

Interactive Application Designer & Developer

Abbtakk News

June 2017 to November 2018

- To design & develop interactive AR, VR & general purpose applications.
- To develop procedures for web, social media and applications.

Database Developer

QVC Softwares.

June 2016 to August 2016

- To develop database using SQL server and Visual C# in a team.
- To integrate the Layout from Visual C# to Database.

Education

Bachelor of Science in Software Engineering

Sir Syed University of Engineering & Technology - Karachi 2014 to 2018

Intermediate in Pre-Engineering

Govt. College For Men - Karachi 2013

Matriculation

Emmi's Institute For Learning - Karachi 2011

Skills

- C#
- Unity Game Engine
- Unity Photon Networking
- IBM Watson for Unity
- Websockets
- Rest API Backend for Unity
- Unity Windows, Mac, Android, iOS
- Virtual Reality (VR)
- Oculus Rift
- Augmented Reality (AR)
- AR Foundation Unity (ARCore, ARKit)
- Vuforia
- Blender
- Substance Painter
- · Pixologic's Zbrush
- · Adobe Photoshop
- Adobe Illustrator
- Adobe Premiere
- Adobe After Effects
- MySQL
- JSON
- Node.js
- Unity .jslib
- Janus Server
- WebRTC

Links

https://www.linkedin.com/in/usamaqh/

Awards

First position at All Karachi Project Competition at Sir Syed University 2018 2018

Our VR project "Devil's Whisper" was awarded First position at All Karachi Project Competition at Sir Syed University 2018.

Regional Finals Winner at Microsoft's Imagine Cup 2018, Islamabad.

Our VR project "Devil's Whisper" won the Regional Finals at Microsoft's Imagine Cup 2018, Islamabad. We were sponsored by Microsoft to attend and compete in the Microsoft's Imagine Cup 2018, Islamabad.

First position at HUPEC FYP competition at Hamdard University 2017 2017

We got First position for our VR project "Devil's Whisper" at HUPEC FYP competition at Hamdard University 2017 for best and innovative FYP project of the competition.

First position at ZUFEST ZURIC Project Competition, Ziauddin University 2017

We held First position at ZUFEST ZURIC Project Competition, Ziauddin University 2017 for our VR project Devil's Whisper.

Project Showcase, HEC at NED University 2017

2017

We were invited to showcase our project "Devil's Whisper" by HEC at NED University 2017.

Called for Motivational speech by Sir Syed University 2018

We were invited in 2018 FYP orientation at Sir Syed University, to motivate and counsel the new batch regarding new technologies emerging and new ideas for projects.

Seminar On Virtual & Augmented Reality - Invited Speaker

2019

Invited to conduct a seminar and speak on the latest trends in the market for Augmented and Virtual reality technologies, to provide the university student's a source of motivation & skillful knowledge.

Certifications and Licenses

Diploma In Graphics Suite, Arena Multimedia.

2012 to 2013

Distinction in graphics suite diploma at Arena Multimedia. Covered range of graphic designing skills, from 2D designing to video editing.